#### Contact

ron@cloudbuilder.io

www.linkedin.com/in/ron-amosa (LinkedIn) ronamosa.io (Personal)

#### Top Skills

Amazon Web Services (AWS)
Cloud Computing
System Administration

#### Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
Samoan (Native or Bilingual)

#### Certifications

CKA: Certified Kubernetes Administrator

CKS: Certified Kubernetes Security Specialist

## Ron Amosa

Senior Platform Security Engineer at Salesforce Auckland

## Summary

Experienced Senior Systems/Cloud/DevOps Engineer now working as a Senior Engineer in Platform-as-a-Service (PaaS) Security.

My main areas of interest and expertise include: Kubernetes, Cloud Infrastructure & Security (AWS, Azure, GCP), Observability, CICD, DevSecOps, Containers, Automation and anything Linux.

## Experience

Salesforce
Senior Platform Security Engineer
October 2020 - Present (1 year 6 months)
Auckland, New Zealand

Remote-first global team providing Security Assurance across Salesforce, Heroku and Mulesoft Cloud Platforms.

Working closely with engineering teams to scope and execute platform application security reviews throughout the development cycle, including architecture reviews and threat models, secure code reviews, and platform and application penetration testing.

Getting a deep understanding of the architecture, infrastructure and application design is key in providing an effective security assessment.

This involves good communication and repoire with our cloud customers (i.e. the engineering teams) to understand their goals and motivations.

Deep-dive research into cloud and web technology, industry best practices, standards and patterns, as well proof of concept, documentation and public blog posts and presentations are all part of the teams day to day work.

Bank of New Zealand DevOps Engineer April 2020 - September 2020 (6 months)

Page 1 of 7

ClearPoint

1 year 3 months

Senior Site Reliability Engineer
October 2019 - March 2020 (6 months)

Auckland, New Zealand

Migration and delivery of Production, Non-Production environments at a major Bank to Infrastructure-as-Code and passing all Security requirements and best practices:

Designing, implementing and orchestrating infrastructure environments as required by the client using following technologies:

- Azure Cloud Provider
- Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)
- Azure Keyvault (with AAD Pod Identity MSI setup)
- Azure Redis
- Azure PostgreSQL
- Istio Service Mesh with mTLS, SDS and Cert-Manager
- Azure AD RBAC integration
- Hashicorp Terraform
- Helm (v3)

Designing, Implementing, Reviewing and Testing Security best practice for Kubernetes (NSP, PSP, container hardening, K8s API security, private loadbalancers, mTLS traffic everywhere)

Managing project people and deliverables; troubleshooting real-time issues; Designing solutions and implementing features and fixes.

Senior Site Reliability Engineer
July 2019 - September 2019 (3 months)

Auckland, New Zealand

Delivery of CI/CD Pipeline solution to help a major Insurance Company realise benefits of continuous deployment and delivery.

Orchestrating and managing multiple development and production environments using the following technologies:

- Azure Cloud Provider
- Kubernetes (k8s) Container Orchestrator
- helm k8s application package and deployment system
- Jenkins
- Hashicorp Vault
- Elastic/Fluent-bit/Kibana stack
- Terraform

Managing project people and deliverables; troubleshooting realtime issues; Designing solutions and implementing features and fixes.

Site Reliability Engineer January 2019 - June 2019 (6 months)

Auckland, New Zealand

Delivery of CI/CD Pipeline solution to help the client realise benefits of continuous deployment and delivery.

Orchestrating and managing multiple development and production environments using the following technologies:

- Azure Cloud Provider
- Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)
- helm k8s application package and deployment system
- Jenkins
- SonarQube
- Hashicorp Vault
- Elastic/Fluent-bit/Kibana stack
- Terraform

Managing project people and deliverables; troubleshooting realtime issues; Designing solutions and implementing features and fixes.

Foster Moore - The Registry People™ Senior Information Technology Consultant December 2017 - November 2018 (1 year)

Auckland, New Zealand

Contract Position consulting, designing and implementing project solution designs to upgrade or enhance BAU systems.

Duties covered the following:

- Reviewing solution designs for projects.

Page 3 of 7

- Providing and/or reviewing estimates on effort required for 'Statements of Work' for clients.
- Writing systems/platform analysis, longevity and options papers for clients.
- Raising changes and implementing project infrastructure tasks.
- Troubleshooting and providing L3 support to operations and any project specific technical support for developers.

#### Technology included:

- Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 & 7
- AWS Cloud Infrastructure
- AWS Security (WAF, Security Best Practices)
- Docker containers (application build & deployment)
- Docker Swarm (container management)
- Terraform, Ansible (AWS infrastructure build & deploy)
- Puppet and Salt (On-Prem server config & deploy)
- Elastic Search/Logstash/Kibana (ELK) stack
- Jenkins-in-Docker build & automation platform
- WSO2 Identity Server (used with SAML/RealMe integration)
- Apache/NGINX reverse TLS proxies
- VMwre vCloud Director for Windows Server Builds.

#### IAG

DevOps Engineer September 2016 - April 2017 (8 months)

Auckland, New Zealand

Contract Position assisting scrum teams on the road to continuous delivery.

#### Working with:

Mulesoft Appservers, Windows Server 2008/2012, Citrix Netscaler, Powershell, VMware, Jenkins, Ruby, Java, SoapUI, JWT, IIS, PHP, REST, SOA, AngularJS, Active Directory, ADFS.

- Lots of troubleshooting of the development environments
- Assisting SCRUM teams in getting their code deployed, tested, and troubleshooting and all lissues.
- Troubleshooting and advising on Production issues and assisting the teams in understanding and fixing any/all problems.
- Implemented and clean up load balancing solutions in NetScaler for API's.

- Maintenance and improvement of development environments and monitoring systems.
- Documentation for services and other knowledge kept up to date.
- Assisted the SCRUM teams to migrate their apps and processes onto the new CI/CD pipeline.

Vodafone New Zealand Senior Systems Integration Engineer September 2012 - September 2016 (4 years 1 month)

Senior Systems Integration Engineer working with:

Weblogic Appservers, Jboss, Sun Webserver, Linux, HPUX, Solaris, Windows 2K, IIS, Oracle Fusion, Websphere Datapower Appliances, Alteon switches, F5 LTMs, VMware VCD, Jenkins, Ruby, Java, Parasoft, Ansible, Puppet.

- Project-focused role being consulted on design, integration and implementation.
- Subject matter expert (SME) on a range of devices and systems, providing input to meetings and support to other teams where needed.
- Implementing the solution and working across multiple teams and functions (infrastructure, networks, operations, architecture etc) to get the solution working, figuring out what was going wrong and providing feedback to the solutions.
- Operational support for deployments and also taking ownership of the deployment of projects deliverables should there be no resource available or the piece was too critical to get wrong.
- Developed scripts (ruby, jython, bash etc) to assist in day to day tasks or furthering the development of existing scripts.
- Troubleshooting and testing support meant getting across an extensive range of technology and systems. Researching, understanding, actioning a fix/solution and then providing feedback to stakeholders and operational teams was a critical part of this role.

I was effective in this role not only because of my technical skills but my ability to understand the project as a whole, what that meant to the business and how to help co-ordinate the various silos to get things across the line.

AOL UK
Application Support Specialist
July 2008 - August 2009 (1 year 2 months)

During my OE in London I successfully applied to an Application Support Specialist position with AOL UK.

Duties included 2nd/3rd Level Support of Internal Applications; diagnosing system errors and escalating accordingly. Frequently used my Unix/Linux skillset for various tasks including migrating services from a Unix to Linux setup; bash/perl scripting for process automation & alarms.

#### **EDS NZ Ltd**

4 years

Unix Systems Administrator May 2004 - July 2008 (4 years 3 months)

Responsible for 900+ UNIX Servers - Solaris/AIX/HP-UX/RHE Linux boxes.

Day to day maintenance and monitoring of systems. Dealing with any OS & Hardware issues, filesystem and user issues.

Analyze and respond to all Unix system issues affected mission critical production environments in Telecom/XTRA, Fonterra, CBA.

Execute any Unix related System Changes as requested - patches, emergency hardware replacements, system maintenance reboots.

# Application Support Specialist 2004 - 2006 (2 years)

Auckland, New Zealand

Demonstrated leadership skills saw me promoted to Shift Team Leader within the first year of the 7-11 account ahead of more senior team members. A natural ability to manage teams saw 'problem' team members moved to my shift team for me to manage, re-train and subsequently re-integrate back into their original shift.

My leadership & management track record saw EDS US CORE Management team initiate the process to promote and move me to the 7-11 CORE management team in Plano, Texas.

Duties & Responsibilities included:

# Management of team(s) monitoring US 7-11 UNIX and windows server environments on a 24x7 basis.

# Application Support - Responsible for all 7-11 Order-processing and Reporting Servers (on HP-UX, Solaris, Windows Server 2003 platforms), including proprietary applications & weekly maintenance & reboots.

# 2nd level response team for all system issues & escalations liaising with other support teams.

# Reported directly to US CORE management team in Plano, Texas.

#### **ICONZ Ltd**

Web Developer January 2001 - December 2003 (3 years)

Developed web sites & applications in PHP/MySQL in a LAMP environment. Administered the Linux Servers (Debian/RH) our Apache Servers ran on.

Sites varied from user homepages to company payment driven websites, shopping cart and account management backends.

Most development in PHP/MySQL with a few projects in ASP .NET

### Education

The University of Auckland

Bachelor of Commerce, International Business, Management · (2010 - 2012)

The University of Auckland

BSc, Computer Science · (1999 - 2001)